AJAY RANWA

Kuchaman City, Rajasthan · 6378337598 Email-ID· LinkedIn Profile · GitHub

IT Professional with experience of working with Data Science and Business Analytics Engineers and have good hands-on python Language which helps me to get practical knowledge of this job. I have Experienced working as a Campus Ambassador that highlights my Leadership qualities and communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2021-PRESEENT

DATA SCIENCE & BUSINESS ANALYTICS, THE SPARKS FOUNDATION

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIP

Things we perform here are to collect data and train a machine with that data and predict the outcomes with the test data.

Our works include day to day tasks perform.

JAN 2021 - FEB 2021

CAMPUS AMBASSADOR, EDFOUL

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIP

Helped our team to build various kinds of led they were working on. Learnt good communication skills and can up with a good leadership quality.

NOV 2020 - DEC 2021

VOLUNTEERING, YOUTH EMPOWERMENT FOUNDATION

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIP

Collection of donations for people's who need help in lock down. Making awareness about our organization to people who don't know about it.

EDUCATION

2017 - PRESENT

B. TECH (HONS.), COMPUTER SCIENCE, BHARTIYA INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING &

TECHNOLOGY

Percentage: 77.00%

YEAR OF COMPLETION: 2017

SENIOR SECONDARY (XII), NARAYANA JUNIOR COLLAGE (TELENGANA BOARD)

Percentage: 88.70%

YEAR OF COMPLETION: 2015

SECONDARY (X), TAGORE INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL (CBSE BOARD)

CGPA: 8.00/10

PROJECTS

- <u>Library Management System (Python)</u>
- Color Detection (Python)
- Real Estate Company prediction (Machine Learning)
- Voice assistant (Python)
- Flappy Bird (Pygame)
- Fake News Detection (Machine Learning)

SKILLS

- Python
- Ms-Excel
- SQL
- English Proficiency (Spoken)

- HTML
- CSS
- Machine Learning
- C Programming